Chamila C. Dharmawardhan, Ph.D

□ ccdxz8@mail.umkc.edu

1 +1(509)201-7496

in LinkedIn

Google scholar

GitHub

Authorized to work in USA (Green Card holder)



Dedicated **computational physicist** with 12+ years of diverse experience in numerical simulation, scripting and data analysis and on HPC and other UNIX based systems. excellent team player with aptitude for planning and conducting interdisciplinary projects.

Skills & experience

languages: Python, TSQL, C++, Java, Fortran, BASH, Perl, Mathematica, Matlab

frameworks: Anaconda, SciKit learn, Pandas, numpy, scipy, TensorFlow, beautifulsoup, bootstrap4, GitHub

HPCC: supercomputers (NERSC, XSEDE, ALCF). PBS, LSF ans SLURM batch queuing systems

Management: Designed interdisciplinary research projects with diverse research collaborations effectively

projects

Facial emotion recognitions via deep learning

2020

Project description.....

- get data with IMDB, TMDB and other data APIs and webscrape with beautifulsoup, Selinium
- Movie dataset analysis and classification of genres using KNN classifier
- Housing price prediction model via multi linear regression model

Pneumonia prediction from X-ray images with CNN techniques

2020

Project description.....

Customer churn analysis of TelCo data

2020

Project description.....

- Customer churn prediction with logistic regression, Decision tree, Random forest, SVC, verity of boosting algorithms.

Employment

Senior Research Associate, Illinois Institute of Technology

2019 - 2020

Development FFT based algorithms for protein docking. Automated structure retrieval using **protein data bank API**. Development of FFT based method (**numpy**, **pandas**) to evaluate binding affinity of protein complexes and building scripts to streamline docking simulations of large databases

Post Doctoral Fellow, Georgetown University

2017 - 2019

2 Publications. Development of accurate and efficient computational methods for bio-macromolecular simulations. building pythons scripts to streamline parameterization and simulation. Collaborated (GitLab) with Laboratory of Computational Biology at NIH for coding potential function for the SSMP model and other projects.

Post Doctoral Fellow, University Colorado Boulder 3 Publications

2016 - 2017

Understanding corrosion of high temperature super-alloys in 4D: experimental/theoretical collaboration. Developed Python tools for force fields building, data handling and visualization of results. Automated calculations and visualizations via python and bash scripting.

Graduate Research Assistant, University Missouri - Kansas City

2011 - 2015

11 Publications. Utilized *ab initio* simulation techniques to gain insight into structure at atomistic level of cement based materials. Developed efficient methods for thermo-mechanical simulations at high temperature. OpenMPI calculations. Troubleshoot software, manage group accounts in supercomputers and mentor students. Mentored three masters students, one undergraduate student, and one visiting scholar.

Education

- 2020 Certificate, Data Science, Flatiron school of computing
- 2015 Ph.D., Physics, University of Missouri Kansas City
- 2008 MS., Physics, Central Michigan University
- 2005 RS., Physics/Mathematics, University of Colombo, Sri Lanka